depositprotection.com 2012-04-24

# 

Department for Communities and Local Government has appointed The Deposit Protection Service as a scheme
administrator to act on its behalf to gather and process the information you provide together with information from other
sources for the purpose of providing a tenancy deposit scheme as regulated by the Housing Act 2004. This includes the
provision of Alternative Dispute Resolution Services.
DATA PROTECTION NOTICE AND PRIVACY POLICY
DATA PROTECTION NOTICE
Uses and sharing of personal information
Your personal information will be used solely for the purpose of providing The Deposit Protection Service, including
alternative dispute resolution services (which may be provided by a service provider nominated by The DPS) save that
DCLG may disclose details of your Deposit Protection Service activities to regulators, industry bodies and other
organisations for the purposes of fraud prevention, money laundering prevention and where there are concerns over your
activities. These other organisations are required to protect your personal information on behalf of DCLG and cannot use
your personal information for purposes unconnected with The Deposit Protection Service.
The DPS will process all personal information on behalf of DCLG in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.
If you access The Deposit Protection Service from a website outside the European Economic Area your personal
information may have to be transferred outside the European Economic Area to enable you to access it.
PRIVACY POLICY
Personal information collected
The DPS collects the information you are asked to provide during your registration with The DPS or which you supply
during the period that any Deposit is protected for you. The DPS’s website and emails use common internet tools such
as cookies (see further below).
DCLG may instruct The DPS to collect information about you from other sources, such as Tenants, land registry data,
postal services data or other sources necessary to conﬁrm your identity or the instructions you provide to The DPS.
Cookies
A cookie is very small text ﬁle which a website transfers to your computer’s hard drive. This allows the website to
recognise that you have visited on a previous occasion, and to automatically restore any preferences that you may
have already set. Only the website that originally posted the cookie can retrieve it. This type of cookie is
semi-permanent, typically having a lifespan of around 3 months. After this time, the cookie expires and is
automatically removed from your computer.
The DPS does not use semi-permanent cookies. It does, however, use what is known as a session cookie. A session
cookie is a standard technique used by many web sites to temporarily store a unique ID on a user’s computer for the
duration of the time you are viewing the web site. This session ID allows the website to maintain continuity throughout
your visit (e.g. keeping you logged-in). Session cookies do not identify you personally and are deleted when the web
browser is closed.
Please note that the websites to which this site may be linked may make use of their own cookies to collect
information from you.
Most browsers will automatically accept cookies, but it may be possible to set your browser to notify you when it is
received, at which point you can choose to accept or reject it. You must allow session cookies for The DPS website to
function correctly.
                                                                                                                    11THOB P26

Your rights
Under the Data Protection Act 1998 you have the right to request a copy of the personal information The DPS holds
about you by writing to us at the address below. There may be a small charge for this service. The DPS tries to ensure
that all information which we hold for you is accurate. If you ﬁnd any inaccuracies please notify us and we will correct
them promptly. Communication with you may be impeded if the information we hold is inadequate or inaccurate.
Security precautions
The DPS employs appropriate technical security measures to protect your personal information and to ensure that it is
not accessed by unauthorised persons. Information is held on secure servers and is encrypted wherever this is
possible. This is the same encryption used to transmit credit card details over the Internet when buying merchandise
online. Our security procedures also provide that, in addition to any password which you may require to gain access to
The Deposit Protection Service, you may have to provide proof of identiﬁcation before we will release personal
information to you. Multiple incorrect attempts or invalidation will result in a lockout from the information. We undergo
independent periodic reviews of our security policies and procedures to ensure that our systems are secure and
protected. You should never divulge your identiﬁcation numbers, username, or password to anyone else. You should
also never write your password down or store it on your computer.
Contact details
Please contact The DPS in the ﬁrst instance at:
The Deposit Protection Service, The Pavilions, Bridgwater Road, Bristol, BS99 6AA. Tel: 0844 4727 000 Online: Enquiry
Forms are available through the Virtual Customer Service Agent or the Frequently Asked Questions
at www.depositprotection.com.
Or you can contact the DCLG at:
The Tenancy Deposit Protection Team, 1/C4 Eland House,
Bressenden Place, London, SW1E 5DU. Tel: 0207 944 4400
Email: contactus@communities.gsi.gov.uk
This data protection notice and privacy policy only applies to this website and does not apply to any websites
from which you may have linked to this website or to any website to which you may link from this website.
                                                                                                                      11THOB P26
